Guide to the Department of University Health, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of University Health, Yale University, records
1911-1964
RU 557
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.75
(13 boxes)
The records consist of administrative files, correspondence, reports, and student and staff records documenting the operations of the Department of University Health at Yale University.
Yale University. Dept. of University Health
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 35 (YRG 35), Records documenting Yale health services.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of administrative files, correspondence, reports, and student and staff records documenting the operations of the Department of University Health at Yale University.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by subject.
College students -- Medical care; Health services administration; Medical care; Universities and colleges -- Health promotion services; Yale University. Dept. of University Health
- Records, 1911-1964; Accession 19ND-A-152
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2040.
  - Accidents: correspondence, clippings, 1938-1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Accidents: statistics, 1934-1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alcohol, 1935-1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Allergy Clinic: proposed, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Andover Corporation Conference, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Angell, James R., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Annual reports, 1916-1944 (Box 1, Folder 7 - 12)
  - Annual reports, 1945-1960 (Box 2, Folder 13 - 14)
  - Applicants: MD, 1945-1953 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Appointments, recommendations, salary increases, 1919-1952 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Athletics
    - Association: general, 1942-1954 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Association: physical fitness statistics, 1942-1957 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - "Athletic Behavior": F.J.Ryan, Ph.D., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Coverage for sports, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Foot treatment, 1931-1947 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Injuries and supervision, 1924-1952 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Research on effects, 1922-1940 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Seminar on psychofogical aspects of athletics and coaching, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Study: history of college athletes, class of 1905 and prior, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - surgical coverage and payments, 1941-1952 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Behavioral change research, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Berkeley Divinity School, 1949-1955 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Biographical information on orthopedic physicians, 1930-1951 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Board of Athletic Control, 1916-1958 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Board of University Health: minutes of meetings, 1916-1965 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Boxing incident: Yale - Harvard, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Brouha, Lucien: biological and psychological research, 1936-1944 (Box 3, Folder 34 - 35)
  - Bursary appointments: forms and applications, 1950-1954 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Campus police, 1943-1960 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Christian Science issue, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Civil Defense, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Cold Study, 1932-1941 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Conference on Public Health Study: Course of Studies for Public Health certificate, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Crew, 1923-1931 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Department of Physical Education, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - "Developing a College Mental Hygiene Service": Bryant M. Wedge, M.D., Undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Diathermy, 1944-1953 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Divinity School, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Employee Health Service, 1943-1948 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Equipment, 1932-1951 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Ewell, John Woodruff: Associate Director, 1946-1955 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Financial Aid, 1949-1957 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Football
    - General, 1930-1950 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Fatalities, 1931-1953 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Helmet Study, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Injury statistics, 1932-1942 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Seabury, Robert, surgeon, 1923-1951 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Food poisoning, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Fry, C. Dr. (photograph), 1936 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Fulbright program, 1950-1952 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Funds: awards, bonds, memorial, 1917-1938 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Furniss, Edgar S.: Provost Emeritus, 1935-1959 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Glee Club, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Greenway, James C.: Head of Department of Health, 1917-1962 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Gymnasium, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Hathaway, John S: Department of Health director, 1948-1955 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Health and Hospitalization coverage: growth and dates, 1924-1956 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Health: miscellaneous, 1919-1950 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Health reports: monthly, 1958-1961 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Heart Study, 1911-1939 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Hockey statistics, 1935-1948 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Hospital and Infirmary occupancy: old graphs, 1930-1952 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Human Welfare Group, 1929-1930 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Hypertension, 1937-1938 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Illumination, 1925-1952 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Infirmary, 1916-1954 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Infirmary Annual Reports, 1942-1950 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Infirmary: Divinity School, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Infirmary: fees and visits, 1948-1955 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Infirmary: history, 1919-1952 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Influenza, 1947-1953 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Inoculations, 1936-1941 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Insurance, 1936-1954 (Box 7, Folder 81 - 82)
  - Inter-College Athletics and Freshman Intermural Athletics, 1958-1960 (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Interim reports, 1922-1955 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Inventory, 1931-1947 (Box 7, Folder 85 - 89)
  - Isotope: general, 1947-1952 (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - Isotope: radioactive hazards and their control, 1947-1958 (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - Laboratory: miscellaneous, 1933-1954 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Laboratory reports, 1942-1946 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Leddy, Percy A., Dr., 1931-1938 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - Mathews, Frank, Dr. (confidential), 1945-1948 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - Medical care costs, 1930-1931 (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - Medical excuses and eventual solutions, 1946-1954 (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - Medical School: miscellaneous, 1930-1952 (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - Mental hygiene, 1929-1960 (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - Mental hygiene: history, 1925-1955 (Box 8, Folder 100)
  - Mental hygiene and psychiatry, 1950-1958 (Box 8, Folder 101)
  - Minutes of the Board of University Health: meetings, 1916-1964 (Box 8, Folder 102 - 103)
  - Miscellaneous: history of Department of Health, 1916-1958 (Box 9, Folder 104 - 105)
  - Muscle Power Studies, 1951-1954 (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - Navy and Marine Corps, 1940-1956 (Box 9, Folder 107)
  - Nolan, Thomas: masseur, Physical Therapy Department, 1946-1947 (Box 9, Folder 108)
  - Occupational health, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 109)
  - O'Donnell, Edward: Physio-therapist, 1942-1959 (Box 9, Folder 110)
  - Orthopedics, 1922-1937 (Box 9, Folder 111)
  - Payne-Whitney Gymnasium Committee, 1932-1939 (Box 9, Folder 112)
  - Payne-Whitney Gymnasium: plans, 1926-1931 (Box 9, Folder 113)
  - Payne-Whitney Gymnasium: report, 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 114)
  - Physical Education, Department of, 1937-1956 (Box 9, Folder 115)
  - Physical Therapy, 1932-1948 (Box 9, Folder 116)
  - Polio, 1942-1959 (Box 9, Folder 117)
  - Printed articles: miscellaneous, 1922-1926 (Box 9, Folder 118)
  - Psychiatry and mental hygiene, 1945-1963 (Box 9, Folder 119)
  - Psychiatric Who's Who of the middle 20's, 1925-26 (Box 10, Folder 120)
  - Public Health, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 121)
  - Rebates: board charges, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 122)
  - Recommendations: MD's, 1941-1955 (Box 10, Folder 123)
  - Red Cross, 1942-1952 (Box 10, Folder 124)
  - Rogers, Orville F., M.D., 1919-1954 (Box 10, Folder 125)
  - Salaries: miscellaneous, 1922-1938 (Box 10, Folder 126)
  - Sanford, Hamilton C.: Business Manager, Alumni Hall, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 127)
  - Sanitation, 1942-1958 (Box 10, Folder 128 - 130)
  - Service Bureau, 1930-1954 (Box 10, Folder 131)
  - Stilbamidine, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 132)
  - Student Appointment Bureau, 1933-1952 (Box 10, Folder 133)
  - Student health, 1942-1948 (Box 10, Folder 134)
  - Student Health Service: Annual reports, 1948-1957 (Box 11, Folder 135)
  - Swimming pool: equipment and sanitation, 1917-1951 (Box 11, Folder 136)
  - Tetanus, 1934-1951 (Box 11, Folder 137)
  - Tuberculosis, 1932-1952 (Box 11, Folder 138)
  - Van Eck, Milton, Dr., 1952-1953 (Box 11, Folder 139)
  - Venereal disease control, 1938-1942 (Box 11, Folder 140)
  - Veterans Administration, 1948-1952 (Box 11, Folder 141)
  - Yale Athletic Association: Annual reports, 1957-1959 (Box 11, Folder 142)
  - Yale Daily News: health articles, 1938-1939 (Box 11, Folder 143)
  - Yale in China, 1917-1923 (Box 11, Folder 144)
  - Yale Institute of Occupational Medicine and Hygiene, 1947-1958 (Box 12, Folder 145 - 146)
  - Yale New Haven Hospital relations, 1935-1945 (Box 12, Folder 147)
  - Yale News, 1943-1947 (Box 12, Folder 148)
  - Yale School of Nursing: Annual reports, 1945-1950 August (Box 12, Folder 149 - 150)
  - Yale School of Nursing: Annual reports, 1950 September-1952 (Box 13, Folder 151 - 153)
  - Yale School of Nursing: miscellaneous, 1944-1951 (Box 13, Folder 154)